<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Anthony Short</title>
  <subtitle>Designer and Frond-End Developer</subtitle>
  <id>http://anthonyshort.me/</id>
  <link href="http://anthonyshort.me/"/>
  <link href="http://anthonyshort.me/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2012-01-27T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Anthony Short</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>My Journey To Kyoto</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2012/01/my-journey-to-kyoto"/>
    <id>/2012/01/my-journey-to-kyoto.html</id>
    <published>2012-01-27T00:00:00+09:00</published>
    <updated>2012-01-27T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Anthony Short</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is the second day traveling by myself in Japan and I&amp;#8217;ve headed from Furano, through Sapporo and down to Kyoto. It was always going to be a bit of a character builder traveling around by myself in a country I didn&amp;#8217;t know and not being able to speak the local tongue. But next couple of days would prove to be the most interesting days yet involving tunnels, new friends and running shoe-less (and almost pants-less) through the airport.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is the second day traveling by myself in Japan and I&amp;#8217;ve headed from Furano, through Sapporo and down to Kyoto. It was always going to be a bit of a character builder traveling around by myself in a country I didn&amp;#8217;t know and not being able to speak the local tongue. But next couple of days would prove to be the most interesting days yet involving tunnels, new friends and running shoe-less (and almost pants-less) through the airport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img alt='Sapporo' src='/images/2012/01/sapporo-1.jpg' /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Snow still blankets the entire city&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;h2 id='going_underground'&gt;Going Underground&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last time I was in Sapporo I was wandering around the city with Justin and we couldn&amp;#8217;t figure out why there were so few people on the streets in the middle of the day on a weekday. It turns out that there are tunnels that run underneath the entire CBD so you don&amp;#8217;t have to walk around in the cold!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;a alt='View Larger Version' href='http://anthy.me/DiGM'&gt;&lt;img alt='Sapporo' src='/images/2012/01/brains.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Braiiiiiinnnnsss...&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up on the surface it was a zombie apocalypse-esque ghost town albeit minus the zombies (unfortunately). But I found the entrance to the tunnel. It was another world down there. There are shops, markets and cafes with literally thousands of people walking through the tunnels &lt;strong&gt;underground!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason the entire time I was down there I was imagining the underground music from Super Mario Bros.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img alt='Some mascot I found in the tunnels' src='/images/2012/01/underground-mole.jpg' /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Wait... A costume wearing a costume?
		&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I managed to snag this photo with this fat, cute thing. I have no idea what this is supposed to be or what they were trying to sell me so I just smiled and handed them my phone to take a photo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='a_night_in_susukino'&gt;A Night in Susukino&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stayed in a very small hostel in Sapporo called &lt;a href='http://tpa.spirallife.jp/english/index.html'&gt;Time Peace Apartment&lt;/a&gt;. It was run by a Japanese couple. The only other people staying there were two Korean brothers roughly my age. After a brief attempt at a conversation we both seem to give up and close the curtains on our beds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img alt='Susukino' src='/images/2012/01/sapporo-2.jpg' /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Susukino has a lot of butt-load of restaurants&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At night I explored &lt;strong&gt;Susukino&lt;/strong&gt;, the trendy, restaurant and club-filled area of Sapporo. I&amp;#8217;d had enough awkward and challenging conversations and found the closest english-speaking pub - &lt;strong&gt;TK6&lt;/strong&gt;. In there I ended up talking to Jonno from Brisbane, Australia who was over here working at the university in Sapporo for a month. Seeing as it was Australia Day the bar was selling Australian beers and food. I didn&amp;#8217;t come to Japan to have Australia food, but we ended up drinking and talking all night. Good beer, good company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s amazing what little adventures you can have you when you just go looking for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='my_pants_im_losing_my_pants'&gt;My Pants! I&amp;#8217;m losing my pants!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day I ended up at the airport at 9:45 when the plane was supposed to be leaving at 10:00am. I had to run with my huge bag to the check-in. After yet another difficult conversation they decided to run with me to the gate. But first I had to pass the checkpoint. They made me take of my belt, my shoes and spent the next 5 minutes searching through my bag. When that was all sorted out we had to run to the gate. I didn&amp;#8217;t have shoes on, or a belt and I had to carry my huge bag whilst running at least 100m to the gate. To top it off my pants need that belt to stay up and my hands were full so I ended up giving the people in the airport terminal a bit of a show as my pants started falling down&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230;and the worst thing about the day is still the fact they took my shuriken at the checkpoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But at least I made it to Kyoto.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>My First Days in Japan</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2012/01/my-first-days-in-japan"/>
    <id>/2012/01/my-first-days-in-japan.html</id>
    <published>2012-01-25T00:00:00+09:00</published>
    <updated>2012-01-25T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Anthony Short</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I arrived in Japan a couple of days ago for the start of an epic 18 day adventure across Japan. I wasn&amp;#8217;t ready for the weather. I knew it would be cold but I didn&amp;#8217;t know it would be &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; cold. I easily forget the bite of a snowy winter when I live in toasty east-coast Australia.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I arrived in Japan a couple of days ago for the start of an epic 18 day adventure across Japan. I wasn&amp;#8217;t ready for the weather. I knew it would be cold but I didn&amp;#8217;t know it would be &lt;em&gt;this&lt;/em&gt; cold. I easily forget the bite of a snowy winter when I live in toasty east-coast Australia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first destination was Furano in Hokkaido (the north island). To get there I had to travel through Sapporo, which is one of the larger cities in Japan, but not very old. We walked out of the train station in Sapporo and had to throw on all of our snow gear to deal with the cold but the locals seemed happy enough walking around in short skirts and t-shirts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img alt='Building in Takikawa' src='/images/2012/01/japan-1.jpg' /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Building in Takikawa where we were stuck for a couple of hours&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We couldn&amp;#8217;t seem to work out what the locals ate for breakfast, so on the first we found a tiny curry shop in Sapporo and had curry for breakfast. I paid for that one a little while later. Justin continued his Japan holiday tradition and had beer with breakfast. The restaurant was tiny and traditional. You walked into the store and were greeted with a friendly &lt;em&gt;ohiyo gozaimasu!&lt;/em&gt;. The lady was very polite and I had a chance to practice my Japanese on a real-life person for the first time. She seemed to understand what I was saying so mission accomplished!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a bit of time to kill in Sapporo because the trains to Furano were cancelled because of heavy snow (which was a good sign for our upcoming snowboarding adventures) so we went and explored Susukino district where all the shops and restaurants are. We found a shop ran by an old man that stocked swords, shuriken, BB guns and a whole lot of inappropriate paraphernalia that wouldn&amp;#8217;t be able to leave Japan. Alas, I walked out of there with a blunt, metal shuriken for ¥1000. Hopefully I can get it back into Australia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img alt='Shuriken I bought in Sapporo' src='/images/2012/01/shuriken.jpg' /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;A blunt shuriken I bought in Sapporo. Hopefully this gets through customs.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We traveled to Furano and met up with the rest of the guys staying at the house and went out for dinner at a restaurant named Sai that had a bbq grill in the centre of each table for cooking your own food. We had deer, pork, beef and what I&amp;#8217;m assuming was intestines. Two bottles of sake later and much meat consumed we ventured out to the local bar called Bridge Bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img alt='Japanese BBQ Restaurant at Sai in Furano' src='/images/2012/01/japan-2.jpg' /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Various meats and onion at Sai, a Japanese BBQ Restaurant in Furano&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bridge Bar is run by an American fellow named Bill who was kind enough to translate a few things for us and just help us out with Japanese culture in general. It&amp;#8217;s called Bridge Bar because he encourages western tourists and local japanese people to &amp;#8216;bridge the language barrier&amp;#8217; and hang out and talk. Bill runs english classes for locals and hosts dinners for his students and tourists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img alt='Bridge Bar in Furano' src='/images/2012/01/japan-3.jpg' /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Bridge Bar in Furano. Bill, the owner, is on the left (half cut off) and helped translate a few things for us as well as having an awesome beer collection.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day, with a mild hangover, we set out to snowboard on the slopes of Furano. I&amp;#8217;ve only been snowboarding a couple of times so my levels of suck are quite high. Nevertheless, we went to the topmost peak of the mountain to start off with. Probably a bad idea. The slopes were extreme steep but we managed to make our way down. The course is huge. It took us a while to get down the roughly 3km run. We spent the day here trying out various courses and going to the other side of the mountain and back via chair lift and snowboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img alt='Top of the slopes in Furano' src='/images/2012/01/furano-mountain.jpg' /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The top of the slopes in Furano. The view was amazing. You can see an active volcano lies near the town in the distance.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We split up the day with some food from the restaurant at the foot of the mountain. I had a delicious ramen noodle soup with egg, beef and seaweed in a chicken broth. It warmed me up and gave me the energy to make my way back out to the mountain for some more awful snowboarding attempts and many falls. While we were there the mountain was covered with children from local schools who appear to do snowboarding and skiing as a school sport. It was amazing watching little kids blaze past me on their skis whilst I was fumbling around on the ground struggling to stand up from my last fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img alt='Trees iced with snow fall from the previous night' src='/images/2012/01/snow-capped-trees.jpg' /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The trees were iced with the snowfall from the previous night at the top of the mountain.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For dinner we found a local sushi train restaurant called Topical Sushi (I&amp;#8217;m fairly sure it&amp;#8217;s meant to say &amp;#8216;Tropical&amp;#8217; seeing as the whole restaurant had a tropical theme and branding). They had great sushi and a great atmosphere. They didn&amp;#8217;t speak much english and there seemed to be more westerners at the restaurant than they were used to. Most of the ordering consisted of a &amp;#8216;sumimasen&amp;#8217; and just pointing at something. I had a lot of food, various fish sushi, sweet potato balls on a stick, octopus and a tasty coffee jelly with coffee ice cream for dessert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, we tried to push on to Bridge Bar but snowboarding all day had made us weary. I tried an american micro-brewery amber ale and cider then we head home to finish off the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img alt='Sushi Train in Furano' src='/images/2012/01/japan-4.jpg' /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Sushi Train restaurant in Furano. They didn't speak any english so it involved a lot of pointing and awkward conversations. Killer crepe cake though.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I noticed since being here was the proliferation of vending machines. They&amp;#8217;re on every corner and sell the craziest drinks I&amp;#8217;ve ever seen — Beer, corn soup, hot chocolate, coffee, green tea, milkshakes. I&amp;#8217;m slowly making my way through all the different drinks but most seem to taste like ass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img alt='Vending machines in Japan selling alcolhol' src='/images/2012/01/vending-machines.jpg' /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Vending machines are everywhere in Japan. They sell alcohol in them as well!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, it&amp;#8217;s been a great trip so far and very eye opening. I&amp;#8217;ve probably learned more Japanese in the last couple of days than in the past year (which isn&amp;#8217;t much anyway). I&amp;#8217;ve felt more comfortable here than in America a couple of years ago, even though I don&amp;#8217;t speak Japanese. Today I&amp;#8217;m heading out on my own to explore the rest of Hokkaido and Kyoto. My first stop is to an onsen (a natural hot spring bath) near Furano then I&amp;#8217;ll make my way back to Sapporo to find my hostel and hopefully I&amp;#8217;ll be able to pick up a copy of the latest Shonen Jump weekly manga magazine so I can read Naruto in it&amp;#8217;s natural habitat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img alt='The ski fields at Furano at the end of the day' src='/images/2012/01/ski-fields.jpg' /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The mountain after a day of hard boarding. Beautiful.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2012/01/hello-world"/>
    <id>/2012/01/hello-world.html</id>
    <published>2012-01-21T00:00:00+09:00</published>
    <updated>2012-01-21T00:00:00+09:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Anthony Short</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;#8217;ve finally managed to put a blog together. It&amp;#8217;s only taken 5 years, dozens of design iterations and now finally I think I have something I can work with. I&amp;#8217;m headed to Japan in a couple of days and decided that this was definitely something I wanted to record somehow. I couldn&amp;#8217;t let this opportunity go to waste.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;#8217;ve finally managed to put a blog together. It&amp;#8217;s only taken 5 years, dozens of design iterations and now finally I think I have something I can work with. I&amp;#8217;m headed to Japan in a couple of days and decided that this was definitely something I wanted to record somehow. I couldn&amp;#8217;t let this opportunity go to waste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I put my mind to it and put this site together in probably 3 hours from start to finish. No Photoshop, just plain HTML. I didn&amp;#8217;t use Sass or Coffeescript. I didn&amp;#8217;t think about design. I just wanted something that would let me write down my thoughts and post funny cat pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m really sick of designs that include icons everywhere. Fancy javascript widgets. Sidebars with links all over the place. People come to blogs to read. That&amp;#8217;s what we should be giving them. I think I&amp;#8217;ve done a bit better in that regard. One thing I am realising as I&amp;#8217;m putting together this quick first blog post is that I definitely need to practice writing more often. Hopefully writing on this blog every week will turn my caveman ranting into intellectual observations about life and the web industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or maybe it will just end up being photos of cats.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
