<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Anthony Short</title>
  <subtitle>Designer and Frond-End Developer</subtitle>
  <id>http://anthonyshort.me/</id>
  <link href="http://anthonyshort.me/"/>
  <link href="http://anthonyshort.me/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2012-01-21T00:00:00+11:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Anthony Short</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="/2012/hello-world.html"/>
    <id>/2012/hello-world.html</id>
    <published>2012-01-21T00:00:00+11:00</published>
    <updated>2012-01-21T00:00:00+11:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Anthony Short</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;#8217;ve finally managed to put a blog together. It&amp;#8217;s only taken 5 years, dozens of design iterations and now finally I think I have something I can work with. I&amp;#8217;m headed to Japan in a couple of days and decided that this was definitely something I wanted to record somehow. I couldn&amp;#8217;t let this opportunity go to waste.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;#8217;ve finally managed to put a blog together. It&amp;#8217;s only taken 5 years, dozens of design iterations and now finally I think I have something I can work with. I&amp;#8217;m headed to Japan in a couple of days and decided that this was definitely something I wanted to record somehow. I couldn&amp;#8217;t let this opportunity go to waste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I put my mind to it and put this site together in probably 3 hours from start to finish. No Photoshop, just plain HTML. I didn&amp;#8217;t use Sass or Coffeescript. I didn&amp;#8217;t think about design. I just wanted something that would let me write down my thoughts and post funny cat pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m really sick of designs that include icons everywhere. Fancy javascript widgets. Sidebars with links all over the place. People come to blogs to read. That&amp;#8217;s what we should be giving them. I think I&amp;#8217;ve done a bit better in that regard. One thing I am realising as I&amp;#8217;m putting together this quick first blog post is that I definitely need to practice writing more often. Hopefully writing on this blog every week will turn my caveman ranting into intellectual observations about life and the web industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or maybe it will just end up being photos of cats.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
